Amanda Seyfried (/ˈsaɪfrɛd/ sy-fred;[1] born December 3, 1985) is an American actress, model, and singer. She began her career as a model when she was 11, then at 15 began an acting career, which initially included recurring parts on the soap operas As the World Turns and All My Children.

In 2004, Seyfried made her film debut in the teen comedy Mean Girls. Her subsequent supporting roles were in independent films, such as the drama Nine Lives (2005) and the crime drama Alpha Dog (2006), she also had a recurring role in the UPN drama show Veronica Mars (2004–06). Between 2006 and 2011, she starred on the HBO drama series Big Love and appeared in the 2008 musical feature film Mamma Mia!.

Her other appearances include leading roles in the black comedy horror film Jennifer's Body (2009), as a call girl in the erotic thriller Chloe (2009), the romantic drama-war film Dear John (2010), and the romantic drama Letters to Juliet (2010). She also stars in the dark fantasy historical romance Red Riding Hood (2011), the dystopian sci-fi thriller In Time (2011), the thriller Gone (2012), the musical drama film Les Misérables (2012), as the title porn actress in the biographical drama Lovelace (2013), and in the comedies A Million Ways to Die in the West (2014) and Ted 2 (2015).