Milena Markovna "Mila" Kunis (/ˈmiːlə ˈkuːnɪs/; born August 14, 1983)[1] is an American actress. In 1991, at the age of seven, she moved from the Ukrainian SSR to Los Angeles with her family. After being enrolled in acting classes as an after-school activity, she was soon discovered by an agent. She appeared in several television series and commercials, before acquiring her first significant role prior to her 15th birthday, playing Jackie Burkhart on the television series That '70s Show. Since 1999, she has voiced Meg Griffin on the animated series Family Guy.

Her breakout film role came in 2008,[2][3] playing Rachel in the romantic comedy-drama Forgetting Sarah Marshall. Her other films include the neo-noir action film Max Payne (2008), the post-apocalyptic action film The Book of Eli (2010), the romantic comedy Friends with Benefits (2011), the comedy Ted (2012), the fantasy Oz the Great and Powerful (2013) as the Wicked Witch of the West , and the film Black Swan (2010), in which her performance gained her worldwide accolades, including the Premio Marcello Mastroianni for Best Young Actor or Actress, and nominations for the Golden Globe Award for Best Supporting Actress and Screen Actors Guild Award for Outstanding Performance by a Female Actor in a Supporting Role.