Scarlett Johansson [ born: Scarlett Ingrid Johansson on November 22, 1984, in New York, New York ] is a Golden Globe nominated film actress. She is the daughter of Melanie Sloan and Karsten Johansson. Her father is Danish and her mother, who is from New York, is Jewish. Johansson has a sister named Vanessa, a brother named Adrian, and a twin brother named Hunter born three minutes after her. Johansson showed a passion for acting at a young age and starred in many plays. She began her acting career in 1994 starring as "Laura Nelson" in North (1994). In 1998, the acclaimed film The Horse Whisperer (1998) brought Johansson critical praise and worldwide recognition. Following the film's success, she starred in many other films including the critically acclaimed cult film Ghost World (2001) and then the hit Lost in Translation (2003) with Bill Murray in which she again stunned critics. Later on, she appeared in Girl with a Pearl Earring (2003). In 2003, she was nominated for two Golden Globes, one for drama (Girl with a Pearl Earring (2003)) and one for comedy (Lost in Translation (2003)). She dropped out of Mission: Impossible III (2006) due to scheduling conflicts. Her next film role was in The Island (2005) alongside Ewan McGregor which earned weak reviews from U.S. critics.