Emily Jean "Emma" Stone (born November 6, 1988)[1] is an American actress.

Stone made her feature film debut in the comedy Superbad (2007). In 2010, Stone starred in the comedy Easy A, for which she received a nomination for the Golden Globe Award for Best Actress – Musical or Comedy. In 2014, she co-starred in Woody Allen's romantic comedy Magic in the Moonlight and Alejandro González Iñárritu's black comedy-drama Birdman or (The Unexpected Virtue of Ignorance). For her performance in Birdman, she was nominated for the Critics' Choice, SAG, Golden Globe, BAFTA, Indie Spirit, and Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress. In November 2014, she made her Broadway debut as a replacement in the role of Sally Bowles in the musical Cabaret, which she performed until February 2015.[2]

Her other films include the romantic comedy-drama Crazy, Stupid, Love (2011), the drama The Help (2011), The Amazing Spider-Man film series (2012–14) as Gwen Stacy and the animated comedy The Croods (2013).