Megan Denise Fox (born May 16, 1986) is an American actress and model. She began her acting career in 2001, with several minor television and film roles, and played a regular role on the Hope & Faith television sitcom. In 2004, she made her film debut with a role in the teen comedy Confessions of a Teenage Drama Queen. In 2007, she co-starred as Mikaela Banes, the love interest of Shia LaBeouf's character, in the blockbuster action film Transformers, which became her breakout role. Fox reprised her role in the 2009 sequel, Transformers: Revenge of the Fallen. Later in 2009, she starred as the eponymous lead in the black comedy horror film Jennifer's Body. Fox is also considered one of the modern female sex symbols and has appeared in magazines such as Maxim, Rolling Stone and FHM.[2][3]

Fox was born on May 16, 1986[4] in Oak Ridge, Tennessee, the daughter of Gloria Darlene (née Cisson) and Franklin Thomas Fox, a parole officer.[5] She is mostly of English ancestry, with smaller amounts of ancestry from elsewhere in Europe.[6] She was raised "very strictly Pentecostal", but later attended Catholic school for twelve years.[7][8] Fox's parents divorced when she was young. Fox's mother later remarried, and she and her sister[9] were raised by her mother and her stepfather, Tony Tonachio.[10][11][12] She said that the two were "very strict" and that she was not allowed to have a boyfriend[13] or invite friends to her house.[9] She lived with her mother until she made enough money to support herself.[13]
