Nicole Lilly (born August 3, 1979)[1][2] is a Canadian actress and author. She won a Screen Actors Guild Award and received a Golden Globe nomination for her role as Kate Austen in the ABC series Lost (2004–10).[3] She is also known for her roles in films such as the psychological thriller Afterwards (2008), the war film The Hurt Locker (2008), and the sci-fi sports drama film Real Steel (2011). She played an Elf, Tauriel, in the fantasy adventure series The Hobbit[4][5] and Hope van Dyne in the superhero film Ant-Man.[6][7]

Lilly was born in Fort Saskatchewan, Alberta, and raised in British Columbia by her mother and her father, a produce manager.[8][1][9] Her father was raised in Nigeria, as her paternal grandparents were missionaries in Africa (her paternal grandfather was a Baptist minister). Lilly has English and Irish ancestry; one of her grandmothers was an English war bride.[10]

Lilly graduated from W. J. Mouat Secondary School in Abbotsford, British Columbia, where she played soccer and was vice-president of the student council.[11] While in college, she worked as a waitress, did "oil changes and grease jobs on big rig trucks", and worked as a flight attendant for Royal Airlines to pay for her tuition.[11][12][13] She grew up Christian and her faith influenced her decision to take part in a three-week mission trip to the Philippines when she was 18.[12][14] Her interest in humanitarian causes and global development led her to major in International Relations at the University of British Columbia.[15]

