Olivia Wilde (born Olivia Jane Cockburn; March 10, 1984)[1] is an Irish-American actress, model, producer and activist.[2] She is well known for her television role as Dr. Remy "Thirteen" Hadley on House (2007–12) and her roles in Tron: Legacy (2010), Her (2013), Drinking Buddies (2013), and Rush (2013). She has a role in HBO's upcoming rock 'n' roll drama, Vinyl (2016).

Wilde was born in New York City.[3] Her mother, Leslie Cockburn (née Leslie Corkill Redlich),[3] is an American-born 60 Minutes producer and journalist. Her father, Andrew Cockburn,[3] is also a journalist. He was born in London, to English parents, and was raised in Ireland. Wilde's uncles, Alexander and Patrick Cockburn, also worked as journalists. Her older sister, Chloe Cockburn,[3] is a civil rights attorney in New York. Her aunt, Sarah Caudwell, was a writer; her half-cousin, Stephanie Flanders, is a journalist; and her paternal grandfather, Claud Cockburn, was a novelist and journalist.

